<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Management on My place to put things</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/management/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Management on My place to put things</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Optimising for trust</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/optimising-for-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/optimising-for-trust/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TDD, BDD, DDD, Agile, SAFe, Scrum, Kanban, XP&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of ways to &lt;del&gt;skin a cat&lt;/del&gt; write code in a professional environment.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I take pride in being a person who is a non-ideologue when it comes to my code. There are many good ways of working, and they are all context-dependent.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can&amp;rsquo;t apply the same things that worked when you were a two-person startup operating out of the proverbial garage and expect them to work once your hypothetical unicorn has reached a thousand-plus developers. Even within the same organisation, processes that work for one team  can be catastrophic when applied to their neighbouring team.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Things that made me think: Enshittification, apathy, and discrimination</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/ttmmt-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/ttmmt-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/tags/ttmmt&#34;&gt;This series&lt;/a&gt; is a place to collect interesting things I&amp;rsquo;ve seen, read, or heard, along with some brief thoughts (often incomplete and/or inconclusive) that they provoked.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-rise-of-whatever---eevee&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://eev.ee/blog/2025/07/03/the-rise-of-whatever/&#34;&gt;The rise of Whatever&lt;/a&gt; - eevee&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is probably the best post about LLMs I&amp;rsquo;ve read, which is probably why I&amp;rsquo;m the millionth person to share it. It really sums up my &lt;em&gt;emotional&lt;/em&gt; reaction to their meteoric rise: &amp;ldquo;ew&amp;rdquo;, basically.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The power of the argument is that it identifies a theme that runs through recent tech changes, of which LLMs are just the latest and greatest example: the lack of care for quality, and the realisation from Big Tech that consumers mostly are fine with mediocre output.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>XTC discusses Basecamp&#39;s Shape-Up</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/xtc-basecamp-shape-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/xtc-basecamp-shape-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last week I facilitated a session at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/eXtreme-Tuesday-Club-XTC/&#34;&gt;XTC&lt;/a&gt;, where we discussed the new product development framework from Basecamp, &lt;a href=&#34;https://basecamp.com/shapeup&#34;&gt;Shape Up&lt;/a&gt;, led by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/thomasankcorn&#34;&gt;Thomas Ankorn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It was a really interesting discussion with people exploring the ideas openly, guided by questions posed by Thomas to get the conversation started.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve summarised the points that came up in the discussion, reconstructed from memory and the collected post-its of scribbles at the end of the evening.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-what-problems-does-this-solve&#34;&gt;1. What problems does this solve?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We started by looking at the positives of the framework, trying to identify strengths that would help mitigate problems we have encountered in our own teams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Temple of Fail</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/temple-of-fail/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/temple-of-fail/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCLAIMER:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;This was not my idea - I picked it up from Jane Nicholson at an &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.meetup.com/eXtreme-Tuesday-Club-XTC/&#34;&gt;XTC&lt;/a&gt; event, who was introduced to it by Jess Gilbert (who in turn, I am told, got it from someone else). This post is just explaining why I believe it can be a useful exercise, not any truly original thinking!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the things that is really important to me is that my team and I keep learning at work. As such, fostering a learning environment is kinda key. I think we do that pretty well at Haplo &amp;ndash; we have hired nearly exclusively early-career developers to our tech team for several years now, and one of the key points most hires mention as to why they join is that they feel it&amp;rsquo;s a good place to learn quickly, with the requisite support early on in their career.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
